<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Latlander</title>
    <link>https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Latlander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Markuss Keidann</title>
      <link>https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/markuss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/markuss/</guid>
      <description>Second-Lieutenant Markuss Keidann is a Latvian commanding officer of the 3rd Courland Battalion (and later, Regiment) under the command of Lieutenant Wilks and the &amp;ldquo;protagonist&amp;rdquo; of the story. Born into a simple family in Aizpute and raised in the baptist faith, Markuss was called to serve the army just before the war started, becoming a brave soldier and officer.
In 1917, Markuss defies general Davilov&amp;rsquo;s orders to protect his brother Kris but continues in the army right until the Battle of Riga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lt. Wilks</title>
      <link>https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/wilks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/wilks/</guid>
      <description>Lieutenant Wilks is a Latvian-Jewish commanding officer of the 3rd Courland Battalion (and later, Regiment). An accomplished commander, Wilks&#39; is sometimes regarded as ruthless or unbending, being called Ol&#39; Wilks or Slavedriver by his soldiers. He is a veteran of the invasion of East Prussia and the fall of Jelgava before the formation of the Latvian Riflemen. After the Christmas Battles in January 1917, he is removed from service after retreating without orders and a mutiny against General Davilov and goes on to have a pivotal role in the Russian Civil War commanding the Red Latvian Riflemen, until returning to fight for the independence of Latvia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris Keidann</title>
      <link>https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/kris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andreispurim.github.io/latlander/docs/wiki/characters/kris/</guid>
      <description>Private Kristoffs Keidann is a Latvian soldier of the 3rd Courland Battalion (and later, Regiment). The younger brother of Markuss Keidann, Kristoffs run from home in April 1914 after being prohibited to join the Riga Symphonic Orchestra by his father and brother. He lost communication with his family when the war started.
He volunteers to join Latvian Riflemen in 1915, but being the youngest in his company, he was often lightly mocked by his fellow soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
