<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latlander</title>
    <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Latlander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/chapters/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/chapters/prologue/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for the bad integration. I&amp;rsquo;m fixing it!
Here&amp;rsquo;s the correct link to the current draft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter I: The Promise</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/chapters/prologue/chapter_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/chapters/prologue/chapter_1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keidann Family</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/others/keidanns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/others/keidanns/</guid>
      <description>The Keidanns are a traditional family hailing from Courland and to some extent, related to the Curonian Kings.
Members #  Elder Keidann #   Elder Keidann, also called &amp;ldquo;Keidann The Warrior&amp;rdquo; was an ancient Kuronian warrior who supposedly lived around the 12th Century. According to oral tradition he lived with his wife and children around Aizpute and was part of his King&amp;rsquo;s retinue. He was called into campaign as the pagans went to war with the Crusaders to defend their land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markuss Keidann</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/markuss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/markuss/</guid>
      <description>Second-Lieutenant Markuss Keidann is a Latvian commanding officer of the 3rd Courland Battalion (and later, Regiment) as a colleague of First-Lieutenant Wilks and acts as the main &amp;ldquo;protagonist&amp;rdquo; of the story. Born in 1895 in Aizpute and raised in the local baptist church, he was the oldest son of Mr. and Mme. Keidann and brother of Kriss Keidann, whom he had a rocky relationship.
Book 1 #  Act I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Keidann</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/old_keidann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/old_keidann/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Old Keidann&amp;rdquo; was the patriarch of house Keidann of Aizpute. He was a freed serf who came to become an Aide-de-Camps to the Old Lord during the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter II: The Lonely Oak</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/chapters/act_i/chapter_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/chapters/act_i/chapter_2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lt. Wilks</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/wilks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/wilks/</guid>
      <description>Lieutenant Wilks is a Latvian-Jewish commanding officer of the 3rd Courland Battalion (and later, Regiment). An accomplished commander, Wilks&#39; is sometimes regarded as ruthless or unbending, being called Ol&#39; Wilks or Slavedriver by his soldiers. He is a veteran of the invasion of East Prussia and the fall of Jelgava before the formation of the Latvian Riflemen. After the Christmas Battles in January 1917, he is removed from service after retreating without orders and a mutiny against General Davilov and goes on to have a pivotal role in the Russian Civil War commanding the Red Latvian Riflemen, until returning to fight for the independence of Latvia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris Keidann</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/kris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/kris/</guid>
      <description>Private Kristoffs Keidann is a Latvian soldier of the 3rd Courland Battalion (and later, Regiment). The younger brother of Markuss Keidann, Kristoffs run from home in April 1914 after being prohibited to join the Riga Symphonic Orchestra by his father and brother. He lost communication with his family when the war started.
He volunteers to join Latvian Riflemen in 1915, but being the youngest in his company, he was often lightly mocked by his fellow soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anna</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/anna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/anna/</guid>
      <description>Anna Freimane is a Latvian nurse of the International Red Cross. The daughter of the baptist pastor of Aizpute and sister to Gustavs, she spend her childhood years in the village, being Markuss&amp;rsquo;s best friend until her family moved to Riga in the aftermath of the violence of the 1905 Revolution.
After the breakout of war, she volunteers to the Red Cross and soon becomes a skilled nurse, taking care of the wounded soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Keidann</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/mother/</guid>
      <description>Mrs. Keidann is a Latvian women, mother of Markuss and Kris Keidann. Born a lutheran, she later married Mr. Keidann and joined the baptist church., becoming one of its&#39; key figures. Pregnant when the 1905 revolution started, she volunteered to help for the wounded in the church, which almost cost her life as the church was burnt down by Russian Forces. After a nasty fall escaping the church, she lost her unborn daughter, and would bear health problems for the rest of her life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Father Freiman</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/freiman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/freiman/</guid>
      <description>Pastor/Father Freiman is a Latvian baptist pastor in Aizpute and the father of Anna and Gustavs until he moves to Riga after 1905. He is later imprisoned alongside other baptist pastors and sent to Siberia until he returns in 1917. After the socialist revolution he flees with his daughter to german-controlled Courland.
Appearance and Character #  He is blind in his right eye.
[To be added]
History #  [To be added]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gustavs</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/gustavs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/gustavs/</guid>
      <description>Gustavs Freiman is a Latvian soldier part of the 5th Zemgale Regiment and the younger brother of Anna. He joins the Latvian Riflemen after the devastating losses of the battle of Death Island. He is unadvertedly responsible for Markuss finding Anna in 1916 and their romance.
In 1917, he fights in the defense of Riga and after the battle is lost, he helps Markuss escape to german-controlled Courland. In the escape attempt, he is captured by the german forces and presumed to be dead until 1918.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cpt. Milgrave</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/milgrave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/milgrave/</guid>
      <description>Captain Milgrave is a Latvian commanding officer of the 2nd Riga Battalion (and later, Regiment). An old experienced commander, he fought in the Russo-Japanese war before being assigned to the Latvian Land Defense units. He first appears in the story during the defense of Jelgava and later reappears in the Death Island and during the aftermath of the Socialist Revolution. His fate is unknown.
Appearance and Character #  He is often refered by the soldiers of the 3rd Courland Regiment as an &amp;ldquo;drunker, smoker, absolutely smashed older version of Wilks&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davilov</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/davilov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/davilov/</guid>
      <description>General Danilov is Russian army general in the 12th Imperial Army and acts as the main &amp;ldquo;antagonist&amp;rdquo; of the first book. He rises to command of both Russian and Latvian forces after the disastrous Russians campaigns in East Prussia and is initially a sucessful commander, but soon turns sour as the tides turn.
A stubborn man, Danilov sends the Latvians to attack after attack in hopes of breaking the german lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bear</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/bear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/bear/</guid>
      <description>The Bear is a Latvian soldier. Born in Latgale, he appears as a minor character during the war, but having a major role during the final phases of the War of Independence.
He is a fierce catholic.
Appearance and Character #  [To be added]
History #  [To be added]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozols</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/ozols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/ozols/</guid>
      <description> [To be added]
Appearance and Character #  [To be added]
History #  [To be added]
MacOS MacOS Content #  Linux Linux Content #  Windows Windows Content #   --</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barder</title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/barder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/secondary/barder/</guid>
      <description>Captain Fritz Barder is a German officer of the 9th Army and the &amp;ldquo;antagonist&amp;rdquo; of the last half and third book. A dark, subtle influence, he fought in Belgium and France before being assigned to the Eastern Front. It is unclear when he first fought in Latvia (he later lies to Markuss saying he was in the western front during the entirety of the war) but by 1917 he was already working in the military police and military intelligence in the Riga front.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/father/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lonelymonday.github.io/Latlander/docs/wiki/characters/primary/father/</guid>
      <description>Sgt. Abrams &amp;ldquo;Abe&amp;rdquo; Keidann (commonly called Mr. Keidann or simply as Father by his sons) was a Latvian Homesteader and Steward for a local german family in Aizpute. He was married to Lavise Keidann and had two sons: Markuss and Kris Keidann.
History #  Before: Abrams was born around the early 1860&amp;rsquo;s in Aizpute to the traditional Keidann family, being raised with a solemn sense of duty and unwavering honor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
